Now that you are acquainted with the
Foursquare API you should be ready to
start analyzing any neighborhood or city
using location data. However we decided
to explore neighborhoods, segment them,
and group them into clusters to find
similar neighborhoods in a big city like
New York or Toronto. To be able to do
that, we need to learn how to cluster
data which is a form of unsupervised
machine learning. So in the next video,
we will learn about a very popular
clustering algorithm, called k-means.
Once you watch the next video and
complete the lab on clustering, you
should be ready to start segmenting and
clustering neighborhoods in different
cities. So in this module,
together we will segment and cluster
neighborhoods in the city of New York.
And now I'll leave you with the video on
clustering.