In this video, I will show you how to
make calls to the Foursquare API to
search for venues, learn more about
particular venues, and explore
Foursquare users. So let's get started.
Communicating with the Foursquare
database is really very easy, all thanks
to their RESTful API. You simply create a
uniform resource identifier, or URI, and
you append it with extra parameters
depending on the data that you are
seeking from the database. Any call
request you make is composed of, we can
call this base URI, which is api.foursquare.com/v2,
and you can request
data about venues, users, or tips. But,
every time you make a call request, you
have to pass your developer account
credentials, which are your Client ID and
Client Secret as well as what is called
the version of the API, which is simply a
date. It is designed to give developers
the freedom to adapt to Foursquare API
changes on their own schedule. In other
words, you request the data to be
returned to you in the format that was
the latest up to the date defined by the
version. In one of the previous videos, we
used Foursquare.com to search for coffee
shops around the Conrad Hotel. How
can we do that using the Foursquare API?
Well it is simple. You simply create a
URI starting with the base URI, and since
you're searching for venues, you use the
venues group. And remember you always
have to pass your Foursquare credentials
along with the version of the API. Again
because we're searching for a particular
type of venues, we use the search
endpoint and pass the address of the
Conrad Hotel as its latitude and
longitude coordinates along with the
search query for coffee shops. This
completes our URI,
so we make the call to the database and
in return we get a JSON file of the
venues that match our query. Remember
this is a regular call and with a
personal developer account, we can make
up to 99,500
similar calls. For each venue, we get
mostly its name, unique ID, location, and
category. Each venue added to the
database is assigned a unique ID. In the
same previous video, we decided to learn
more about one of the coffee shops that
were returned by Foursquare, namely Kaffe 1668. Now how can we do that using the
Foursquare API? Again it is very simple; it's only a matter of creating a URI
with all the correct parameters. In this
case, we're still dealing with venues, so
we append the base URI with the venues
group along with our credentials and the
API version. and then, we simply add Kaffe
166'0s unique ID to the URI. And that's it.
This completes our URI, so we make the call
to the Foursquare database and in return,
we receive a JSON file containing all
the information the database has about
Kaffe 1668. Actually with a personal
account, we only get two tips and photos
per venue and not the entire list of tips.
And remember that this type of call is
premium so with a personal account we
can only make 500 similar calls per day.
When we run this query for any venue, we
mostly get the venue's name, URL or
website if they have an online presence,
unique ID again, average rating, location,
contact information ,menu, and statistics
in terms of the number of check-ins, and
finally, tips posted about the venue. The
next thing we did was check out the tips
posted about Kaffe 1668. Doing that using the Foursquare
API is pretty simple. You build the same
exact URI as the one you built to
learn more about the venue itself, but
then you append the unique ID with the
tips endpoint. Then you proceed as usual; you make the call to the database and in
return you get a JSON file with only two
tips since we have a personal account.
And remember that with premium calls
you're limited to 500 calls per day.
Another thing we did when exploring
Foursquare.com was exploring a
Foursquare user. In the video, we explored
the page of Jessica whose tip was the
first in the tips section of Kaffe 1668.
How can you get all the information
about a user using the API? It's
basically the same concept as querying
for venues except that instead of using
the venues group we use the users group.
And along with our credentials and the
API version, we append the user's group
with the unique ID of the user. Just like
venues, also each Foursquare user is
assigned a unique ID, which is
essentially used to retrieve all the
information pertaining to them. Now calls
made to retrieve information about users
are regular calls, so with a personal
account we can make up to 99,500
similar calls per
day. The database returns a JSON file
containing all the data it has about the
user. For each user, we mostly get their
first and last name, their gender, contact
information, unique ID, any Foursquare
friends they have, and their tips. In the
next video, we will learn how to make
calls to explore a location and how to
retrieve trending venues around a given
location. So I'll see you in the next
video.