In this video, we will continue learning
how to use the Foursquare API to
retrieve data from the Foursquare
database, and I'll show you how you can
use the API to explore a location and to
get trending venues around a point of
interest. The last thing we did in the
video when we were exploring Foursquare. com
was trying to find the popular
spots around the Conrad Hotel. How do we
do that using the API? Well we use the
venues group but we use the explore
endpoint instead of the search endpoint,
and we pass the latitude and the
longitude coordinates of the Conrad
Hotel along with our credentials. Then we
make the call to the database and in
return we get a list of the popular
spots around the Conrad Hotel. Just like
with the search endpoint, for each venue
we get mostly its name, unique ID,
location, and category. Another cool thing
you can do with the Foursquare API is
getting trending venues nearby.
These are venues that have the highest
foot traffic when the call to the
database is made. Therefore the results
vary depending on when the call is made.
So in the morning you might find that
trending venues are coffee shops or
office spaces whereas in the evening
trending venues can be malls, museums or
parks. And to get the trending venues, you
simply use the trending endpoint along
with the credentials and the latitude
and the longitude coordinates of the
place of interest. You make the call to
the database and you get a JSON file of
the trending venues that are nearby.
In the JSON file, for each trending venue,
we get mostly its name, unique ID,
location, and category.