Before we end this module, let's recap
what we can do with the Foursquare API.
So using the Foursquare API, we can
search for specific type of venues or
stores around a given location. And it is
important to remember that for this data,
we make a regular call to the API, and if
you have a free personal developer
account ,you can make up to approximately
99 thousand regular calls per day. We can
also learn more about a specific venue
or store or shop, like their full address,
their working hours, and their menu if they
have one, and so on. It's also important
to remember that for this data, we would
need to make a premium call and with the
personal developer account, you
can make approximately 500 calls per day.
Also with the Foursquare API, we can
learn more about a specific Foursquare
user, their full name, and any tips or
photos that they have posted about
venues and stores. For this data, a
regular call to the API would be made.
Furthermore, we can explore a given
location by finding what popular spots
exist in the vicinity of the location,
and for this data a regular call to the
API would be made. And finally, with the
Foursquare API, we can explore trending
venues around a given location. These are venues with the highest foot traffic at
the time this regular call to the API is
made. That's it for now. I'll see you in
the next video.